Homura-chan, I'm sorry.
I'm going to become a magical girl.
Madoka...
You can't!
I finally know what I want.
I've found the wish I truly want granted.
So I'll use my life for that wish.
Don't!
Because then, what have I...
What have I been fighting for?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
But I believe it's because you've protected me for so long and placed so much hope on me
that I'm the person I am now.
I really am sorry.
This is the answer I've finally found.
Please believe in me.
I promise that what you've done
for me will not be in vain.
Madoka...
Now that you're the central point of karmic destiny from many different timelines,
no matter how enormous the wish,
you will most likely be able to realize it.
You're telling the truth, right?
Now, Kaname Madoka...
what is the wish you will pay for with your soul?
I...
I want to erase all witches
before they are even born.
I will erase every single witch in
every universe, past and future...
with my own hands.
If that wish...
If that wish were to come true, it wouldn't just
be on the scale of temporal manipulation...
You'd be opposing karmic destiny—
the very laws of causality themselves!
Do you truly intend to become a god?
I don't care what you call it.
All those magical girls who held onto their
hopes and fought against witches...
I don't want to see them cry.
I want them to stay smiling until the end.
If any rule or law stands in my way...
I will destroy it. I will rewrite it.
That is my prayer. That is my wish.
Now grant it, Incubator!
My very best friend
Finale
Kaname-san, do you truly understand just how daunting that wish is?
I think so.
It means you must fight without pause throughout all timelines, past and future, for all eternity.
It means you'll cease to exist as an individual.
Death would be a kinder fate.
You'll be firmly implanted in this universe as a concept—a principle that destroys witches.
That's fine. That's what I intend to do.
If someone says it's wrong to have hope,
I will tell them they're wrong every single time.
I know my determination will never waver.
It's fine, then, isn't it?
If you think you can do it,
you've just gotta do it!
I mean, you've found your
reason to fight, haven't you?
You've decided yourself
not to run away, right?
That's all there is to it!
All that's left is to run full steam ahead!
Yeah.
Thanks, Kyouko-chan.
I guess that means you'll
be needing this again.
Here you go.
You're not just making
people's hopes come true.
You're becoming hope itself.
The hope of us all.
I won't let your prayers end in despair.
None of you have to hate anyone, or curse anyone...
I'll bear the full, dreadful weight of all your karmic destinies.
So please, believe in yourselves until the very end.
It's okay.
It's okay now.
You don't have to hate anyone anymore.
You don't have to curse anyone anymore.
I'll go back, before you took that form,
and shoulder that burden for you.
Where am I...?
The universe is realigning itself in accordance with the new laws Madoka has brought forth.
Oh, that's right. You were also a user of temporal magic.
Well, then, let us witness together...
what kind of end the existence known as "Kaname Madoka" will meet.
That is the Soul Gem her prayer created.
That much...
Can you even begin to grasp the
amount of despair Madoka must bear
as the price for her immense wish?
She was able to bring forth enough hope to give birth to an entire universe.
But that much hope also brings with it
enough despair to end a universe.
It's only natural.
Don't worry. It's okay.
My wish was to erase all witches.
If that really comes true,
then even I will have no reason to despair!
Madoka, your life no longer
has a beginning or an end.
Not a single trace or memory of your life on Earth will remain here.
Your existence has shifted onto a higher
plane, and you remain only as a concept.
No one can perceive you, and likewise,
you cannot interact with anyone else.
You are no longer part of this universe.
What's that supposed to mean?
Are you trying to say this is the ending Madoka wished for?
You think this is a fair reward for everything she's done?!
You can't be serious!
This is worse than dying...
So much worse...
No. You're wrong, Homura-chan.
As I am now, I can see everything that ever has or will have happened.
All the universes that could have been,
and those that may yet come to be.
Every single one.
Madoka...
That's why I know.
I know just how hard you tried to help me across all those timelines.
I know it all.
I saw the countless tears you shed,
and the countless wounds you bore,
and yet you kept going, all for my sake.
I'm sorry I never knew until now.
I really am.
It wasn't until I became this way
that I could truly know who you were.
I found out that I had such a great
friend by my side this whole time.
I'm so glad I know now.
Homura-chan, thank you.
You were my very best friend.
But now you can't go back home, and you'll be separated from everyone you cared about!
Will you really be trapped here all alone, for all eternity?!
I'm not alone.
Everyone... Everyone will always be with me.
Because from now on, I'll be everywhere,
throughout all of time and space.
So even if you can't see or hear me,
I'll be right there by your side.
Are you really all right with that, Madoka?
Even though I'll forget you?
Even though I won't even know you're there?
Hold on.
It's too early to give up.
You followed me all the way out here, after all.
So even after you've gone back to your world,
you just might be able to remember me.
It'll be all right.
I just know it will.
We just have to believe.
Madoka...
After all, magical girls make hopes and dreams come true!
I'm sure if it's small enough,
a real miracle just might happen.
Don't you think?
Madoka, don't go!
I'm sorry. I have to go guide everyone else.
I'll be able to see you again someday.
So I'll just say goodbye to you until then, okay?
Madoka!
Number 25, Kamijou Kyousuke.
I'll be playing Ave Maria.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
No, I'm sorry too.
The only way I could save you would be
to make it like none of this had happened,
which means that this future
would have to disappear as well.
But I got the feeling that you didn't really want it to turn out like that.
I truly value your wish and all
the hard work you put into it.
I don't think it was pointless in the end at all.
That's why...
Yeah.
This is fine.
I guess all I really wanted was to hear him play one more time.
I wanted more and more people to be able to experience it.
Now that I've remembered that, I'm satisfied.
I don't have any more regrets.
Well, I am a little upset about the way things turned out,
but I can't be mad at Hitomi.
She's almost too good for him,
so she'll make him happy, won't she?
Yeah.
Let's get going, shall we?
Sayaka?
Where's Sayaka?
What happened to Sayaka?!
She's gone.
She followed the Way of the Cycle and passed on.
Miki-san used up all of her power in that last attack, didn't she?
That idiot! What good was saving the
guy she loved if she vanished herself?
Dummy... Just when we'd finally become friends...
That's the fate of all magical girls.
I'm sure you were told that
when you attained this power.
Before the hope we wished for brings
about an equal amount of misfortune,
we have no choice but to vanish from this world.
Madoka...
Akemi-san?
Madoka?
Who's that?
Madoka
Madoka! Madoka!
Yep. That looks just like her.
No, Tatsuya. That's not nice.
You shouldn't pull a girl's hair, okay?
Madoka! Madoka!
I'm sorry. Are you all right?
I'm fine. Sorry for bothering you.
Madoka, right?
Yeah!
Here I come!
Over here!
She's this invisible friend he
plays with when he's alone.
It's pretty common for children, I guess.
Yes. I remember her too.
Do you know her as well?
Is she a character from
an anime or something?
I'm not sure.
I feel like I've heard her name,
but I can't quite place it.
I see.
I wonder if I saw her somewhere with Tatsuya.
Sometimes that name just sounds really familiar.
Madoka...
I see.
Those ribbons are really cute!
And they're just the kind I like!
I'm kind of surprised.
Would you like them?
They wouldn't look good
on an old woman like me.
If I had a daughter, I'd probably get her to wear them.
I see.
Theoretically, I suppose the system you described could have worked.
It's not a theory. It really happened.
Even so, we have no way of proving it.
If the rules of the universe really were rewritten as you say,
we'd have no way to verify that now.
And since you're the only one
who remembers that world,
there's no way to tell if your memories are real or simply imagined.
Well, it is true that even we can't explain why
Soul Gems simply disappear when they can no longer be purified.
That's why these "witches" in your story are such an interesting concept.
As a means of collecting human emotional energy, it certainly has its appeal!
If such a convenient means
had been available to us,
we Incubators might have employed a very different strategy.
Of course. That's the kind of creatures you are.
But in the world you mentioned, there weren't any wraiths like the ones we fight here, right?
Gathering despair must have been a much faster process.
It wasn't as simple as that.
We weren't exactly on the greatest terms with you.
I really don't get human values at all.
Just because witches are no
longer born into this world
doesn't mean the curses harbored by mankind have ceased to exist.
The distortions of the world
have merely changed form,
and now prey on people from the shadows.
The miasma is pretty thick tonight.
These wraiths are just popping
up one after the other.
There's no end to them.
Complaining won't get us anywhere.
Let's go.
This irredeemable world may be nothing but a cycle of sadness and hatred,
but even so, this was a place that she wanted to protect.
I remember that.
And I will never forget it.
That is why...
I will keep on fighting.
I'll never forget the promises we exchanged
I still see it when I close my eyes
I'll move forward as I cast off
this darkness engulfing me
How long will it be before
I see that lost future again?
I'll walk upon this Earth,
and pierce this shadowy veil of unease,
as many times as necessary
The clock that's endlessly ticked away
now tells of the beginning
Let's open the once-closed door,
with these unwavering feelings
My heart started racing once again to paint the future
Even if I get stuck in a maze,
the beautiful blue sky will always be waiting for me
So I won't be afraid
No matter what happens next, I won't give in
Keep it up.
Yeah.